You're the priest?
神官様 あなたが
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
Did you know I would come here too?
私がここに来る事も知ってたの
はい
Yes.
僕は神様の声を皆に伝えるのが仕事
My job is to convey God's voice to the people.
I hope everyone is happy
I hope everyone is well
God teaches me everything there is to know about this world.
I hope everyone is happy
I hope everyone is well
この世界のあらゆる事を神様に教えて貰うんです
I hope everyone is happy
I hope everyone is well
What do you mean by your "job"?
I hope everyone is happy
I hope everyone is well
なにが仕事だよ
I hope everyone is happy
I hope everyone is well
You don't make any money.
All you do is pray every day.
金も稼いでないくせに 毎日祈っているだけじゃん
Hurry and take off your dirty clothes!
ほら 泥も早く抜いて
You were driven out of the castle for making dubious claims about hearing God's voice, you know.
大体
神の声とか胡散臭い事言ってるから
城から追い出されたんでしょう
Why were you driven out of the castle?
どうして追い出されたの
呆れだ
I'm surprised.
You lived in the castle, but you didn't know?
城に居たくせに 知らないの
Episode 7:   Destiny
Move, move! Out of the way!
はいはい そこ退いて
You lived in the castle, but you didn't know?
城に居たくせに 知らないの
I didn't even know what was
happening within the castle.
私は 城の中の事も知らない
Hak! Hang in there!
ハク しっかり
Can you hear my voice?
私の声が聞こえる
ハク
Hak!
持ってて
Hold this.
退いて
Move.
He has a fever.
熱があるな
Hak...
ハク
I've treated it, but the fever
won't break for a while.
処置はしたけど 暫らくは熱引かないよ
今晩が峠ってとこから
Tonight will probably be the worst of it.
Save Hak!
ハクを助けて
I'm working on it.
I don't want him dying on me.
やってるよ 死なれると面倒だし
But I'm not a doctor.
でも俺は医術師じゃない
Don't just assume I can save him.
助けて貰うのが当然たと思わないで
あんた まだ助けた礼の一言もないじゃない
You still haven't thanked me for saving you.
此奴にも一度でも礼を言った事もあるの
And what about him?
Have you ever thanked him?
死にかけてまであんたを守ってんのに
He nearly died to protect you.
It's all right.
大丈夫
まだ死神様のお迎えは来てないから
The god of death hasn't come for him yet.
彼が戻ってきます
He'll come back.
Yun, you should be kinder.
ユン君 言葉優しく
But I hate kings and nobles and people like that.
だって嫌いなんだもん 王とか貴族とか
In her own way, she's fighting.
彼女も彼女的に闘ってる
少しお散歩しませんか
Would you like to go for a walk?
ユン君の薬はとても効くんですよ
僕も何度も救われました
Yun's medicines are very effective.
He's saved me countless times.
て...て...て
Ouch.
Are you okay?
大丈夫
Why do you live out here?
なぜここで暮らしてるの
流れのままに生きているうちに
自然とここへ辿り着きました
I was going with the flow,
and I ended up here naturally.
これでは答えになってないでしょうか
I suppose that doesn't answer your question.
ただ
It's just...
Even here, there are flowers that bloom.
こんな場所にも咲く花があるんですよ
あの
Um...
ありがとう 助けてくれて
Thank you for saving me.
教えて欲しいの 貴方達神官の事
I'd like you to tell me about the priests.
I may not know anything now,
but I don't want to remain ignorant.
私は何も知らないけど アホのまま居たくない
Actually, I'm not a priest.
訂正するけど 俺は神官じゃないよ
I just take care of that useless priest who can't even look after himself.
あの生活力のない のほほん神官の面倒を見てるだけ
Long ago,
昔 神官は王をしても侵せない権威を持っていたんだよ
priests had greater influence than even the king.
Than even the king?
王も
Yeah. They were revered as messengers of God.
そう 神の使いと崇められてたからね
国の政に深く係わり
Priests were deeply involved in ruling the kingdom,
時には戦争をも左右した神官
and sometimes they influenced wars.
神がお怒りだからと 王を降ろされた者まで居たんだよ
One priest even deposed a king,
saying he had angered God.
So priests became a problem for the king.
そこまで来ると 王にとっては厄介な訳
During King Ju-nam's reign,
the Kingdom of Kouka was expanding
ジュナム王の時代 高華国は
他国にも領土を広げ 勢い付いていた
into other kingdoms' territories and growing stronger.
Apparently, Prince Yu-hon's
achievements played a major role.
そこにはユホン王子の功績が大きかったんだって
For Yu-hon,
そんなユホンにとって
priests that could threaten
the king's power were a nuisance.
王の力を脅かす神官は邪魔だったんだよ
So that's why my uncle drove
the priests from the castle.
だから伯父上は城から神官を追い出したのね
Isn't living in the middle of nowhere difficult?
こんな何もない所で大変ではない
Not at all.
俺は人里めんどういし イクスはここの方が落ち着く
I find villages troublesome,
and Ik-su can relax more easily here.
Villages are full of poor people.
人里は貧しい人間で溢れてる
豊かなのは都の一部だけ
Only certain cities are wealthy.
イクスは優し過ぎだから
Ik-su is too nice.
全てを助けようとしてできなくて
He once tried to help everyone.
心が病んだことがある
He became depressed when he couldn't.
彼奴は俺が居ないとダメなの
He can't live without me.
ありがとう
Thank you.
また教えてね
Teach me more sometime.
Hak's gone?!
ハクが居ない
Hak...
ハク
ハクのバカ
Stupid Hak!
心外な
I'm appalled.
暗闇で座り込むなり 悪口ですかい
You're sitting in the dark, badmouthing me?
奇跡の生還を遂げてお元気そうで何よりです
"I'm glad you made a miraculous recovery and seem to be feeling well."
どうしました 怖い夢でも見ましたか
What's wrong? Did you have a scary dream?
そんな事じゃ泣かないわ
I wouldn't cry over that.
Oh?
どこ行ってたのよ
Where were you?
I was looking for this.
ちょいとこれを探しに
Then you should've woken me!
だったら私を起こしなさい
I understand. You can't sleep alone.
なるほど 一人じゃ寝られないんですからね
添い寝しましょうか
Should I sleep next to you? Here.
You fool!
戯け者
You're injured.
そんな怪我で
Now I'm a fool?
今度は戯け
こんなにボロボロになって無茶して
You're behaving recklessly
when you're a total wreck!
I thought you were going to die.
死んじゃうと思った
勝手にいかないで
Don't go off without saying anything!
You have to stay by my side!
ハクだけは側に居なきゃダメ
I want to die now.
なんか 死にてぇな
Huh?
その不細工な泣き顔が結構きたんで
I've had all I can take of that ugly crying face.
I really want to die...
一遍死んで あんたがどんだけ泣くのか すげぇ見たい
and see how much you'd cry then.
Crash
If it's not okay, just turn your head.
嫌なら避けて下さい
Not okay?
嫌？
熱測るのかと思って頭突き出しちゃった
I thought you wanted to check your temperature, so I stuck my forehead out.
違うの
Wasn't that it?
Oh, right.
あぁ そうなんです
熱で頭がおかしくなってで
The fever's making me irrational.
でもさっきよりは引いてる
It's come down, though.
How dumb
m 537 188 l 544 140 600 112 685 122 718 124 729 143 744 162 657 181
髪が
Your hair...
I'm sorry. It was my fault.
申し訳ありません 俺の落ち度です
I don't mind. It's lighter now.
平気よ 軽くなったし
Besides,
それに私 この赤毛がずっと嫌い
I've always hated my red hair.
I love your hair, Yona.
私は好きですよ ヨナの髪
悪くないでしょう こう言うのも
This isn't so bad, is it?
そうですね
You're right.
She says I have to stay by her side
as though that's easy.
側に居なきゃダメ何て 簡単に言ってくれる
頭は悪いですけど 髪はいいんじゃないですか
Your brains might not be so good,
but your hair's all right.
I should sew your mouth shut.
その口 縫い付けてやる
束ねる髪が無くなっても
Even though she doesn't have enough hair to fasten,
she still hasn't thrown away that hair ornament.
まだあの簪を捨ててないくせに
え 神官の家
Huh? The priest's house?
ここは
This place?
Yes.
What a coincidence.
すげぇ偶然
I know you're living in hiding,
しかし 隠れ住んでるとは言え
but I would've expected a priest's house to look more like a shrine.
神官の家つったら もっと祠的なとこと思ったけど
ちょっと 勝手に食べないでよね
Hey! Don't eat that without asking!
おぉ 神官様 お恵みを
Please, priest, grant me your hospitality.
I'm not the priest!
俺は神官じゃないよ
神官様 どこに居たのかな
Where did the priest go?
神官様
Priest?
どうしたの
What's wrong?
I was dreaming about you.
あなたの夢を見ていました
あなたをこの世界の夢を
A dream about you and this world.
ヨナ姫 神の声を聞きたいですか
Princess Yona, would you like
to hear the voice of God?
ムンドクに神官様に道を示して頂くよう言われたの
Mun-deok told me to have
the priest show me my path.
Is a path something that must be shown to you?
道とは誰かに示して貰うものですか
I thought I was supposed to sit still
and not do anything.
私は何もしないでじっとしてるべきなのかと思っていた
But now that I've been chased, Hak nearly killed,
でも追われて
ハクは殺されそうになって自分も死にかけて
and nearly died myself,
my blood is so hot that it's practically boiling.
血が熱くて 沸騰しそうに熱くて
私だって自分の足で立って歩ける
I can walk on my own two legs.
生きたいと思ったの
I want to live.
I won't let anyone take my life or Hak's.
私もハクの命も決して奪わせやしない
私の願いは今はただそれだけ
That's my only wish.
I have nothing to ask of God.
神様に聞く事何て
いいえ あなたが生きると言う事は
普通に平和に暮らすとは違う
No. For you, living doesn't mean spending your days in ordinary peace.
Huh?
あなたが生きると言う事は
この高華国を揺るがす嵐を起こすと言う事
Your life will create a storm that will shake the Kingdom of Kouka.
Priest?
神官様
あなたがただ真っ直ぐに生きたいのなら
If you wish to simply live an honest life
熱き血潮を止められぬのなら
and cannot stop the hot blood in your veins,
I will convey the voice of God to you.
あなたに神の声を伝えましょう
闇 落つる大地
When darkness falls upon the land,
the dragons' blood will restore life once more.
龍の血により 再び蘇らん
In accordance with the ancient pact,
In accordance with the ancient pact, when the four dragons are gathered,
古の盟約に従い 四龍集結せん時
when the four dragons are gathered,
the sword and shield that protect the king will awaken.
王守護する 剣と盾が眼覚め
The red dragon will return at dawn.
ついに赤き龍 暁より還り給う
Flump
Conveying God's voice requires spiritual strength.
神様の声を伝えるのは精神力が要るので
Quit acting so feeble, you faker.
面倒くさいよ 若年寄り
I don't know what this business
is about dragons or gods,
龍とか神とかさっぱり分からんが
but I'm not buying anything
this crackpot is selling!
何を言われても俺は壺は買わん
Crackpot
He's not selling anything.
売らねぇよ
Crackpot
Does the "red dragon" in the prophecy mean the mythological king?
さっきの予言 赤き龍って神話に出てくる王の事
You're familiar with the kingdom's creation myth?
建国神話はご存知で
Yes.
The red dragon god took on human form
赤き龍神が人間の姿になって
and descended from heaven to rule a kingdom on Earth.
天界から地上へ降り 国を治めていく話
He was the first king of Kouka, King Hiryuu.
それが高華国初代の国王 緋龍王
My father used to tell me about him all the time.
父上は昔よく話してくれたわ
But once King Hiryuu became human...
でもその緋龍王も人の身となってからは
...he eventually had to fight humans.
いずれ人と争う事になったのです
The people's hearts filled with evil,
人々の心は邪に満ち
they forgot their god, and their country fell to ruin.
神を忘れてゆき 国は荒れた
Even King Hiryuu was captured by humans who desired power.
緋龍王も権力を欲する人間達に捕えられた
Just when everything seemed
on the brink of destruction,
あわや討ち滅ぼされそうになった時
four dragons descended from heaven.
天界から四体の龍が舞い降りた
"Hiryuu, we have come for you.
緋龍 貴方を迎えに来た
Let us destroy the humans, who have forgotten their faith, and return to heaven!"
信愛と学びを忘れた人間など滅ぼし天界へ帰ろう
Hiryuu rejected them.
緋龍はそれに応じなかった
"No, I am human now.
いや 我はもう人間だ
人に憎まれ 人に裏切られても 人を愛さずにいられないのだ
Though the humans may hate me and betray me,
I cannot help but love them."
龍達もまた 緋龍を愛し失いたくないと願った
The dragons loved Hiryuu as well
and did not wish to lose him.
In order to protect Hiryuu,
四体の龍は緋龍を守るため
they gave their blood to human warriors and granted them strength.
人間の戦士に自らの血を与え 力を齎した
One gained sharp claws that could tear anything apart.
ある者は 何をも引き裂く 鋭い爪を
ある者は 彼方まで見通す目を
One gained eyes that could see across great distances.
ある者は 天高く跳躍する足を
One gained legs that could jump high into the sky.
ある者は 傷つかない頑丈な体を
One gained a strong body that could never be injured.
"You are now our other halves.
これよりお前達は我々の分身
You will serve Hiryuu as your master, protecting him with your lives.
緋龍を主とし 命の限りこれを守り
You will love him and never betray him."
これを愛し 決して裏切るな
With the power of the dragon gods,
龍神の力を手に入れた戦士達は
the warriors led their tribes to protect Hiryuu and brought order to the kingdom.
部族を率い 緋龍王を守り 国の混乱を鎮めた
Before long, the red dragon grew
tired of fighting and fell asleep.
やがて 闘い疲れた赤き龍は眠りにつき
The mission of the four dragon warriors thus ended.
四龍の戦士達は役目を終えた
They thought of their king,
no longer moving, and wept.
彼らはもう動かない王を思い泣いた
They did not know whether they grieved the loss of someone precious,
大切な人を失った悲しみなのか
自身の中にある龍神の血が緋龍の死を悲しんでいるのか
or if the dragon god blood within
them mourned Hiryuu's death.
彼らには分からなかった
それから四龍の戦士達は
自らの力を人の手に余るものと部族の元を去り
Realizing their power was beyond human control,
部族の元を去り
the four dragon warriors left
their tribes and disappeared.
それぞれいずにかへ消えたと言う
残された部族は独自の発展を遂げ 今の五部族となったのです
The tribes they left behind continued
developing on their own,
forming the five tribes of today.
建国神話
The kingdom's creation myth...
それが私に何の関係か
What does that have to do with me?
ヨナ姫は生きたいと言いましたね
You said you wanted to live, correct?
はい
Yes.
でも一人では生きられない
But you cannot live on your own.
If you leave this place, your life
will be in danger again.
外に出れな また命を狙われるから
貴方の側には貴方を支えるハク殿が居る
You have Master Hak supporting you.
しかし このままではハク殿は死にます
However, at this rate, Master Hak will die.
ちょっとまって 勝手に殺すな
Hey, wait. Don't write me off like that.
神の声なんざ 俺は聞こえねぇ そんな...
I can't hear the voice of God. I'm not-
脅しかけても布施は出さんか...ら...な
I'm not giving you alms, no matter how much you threaten me.
この様に 非常にやばい
As you can see, the situation is grave.
貴方には味方が必要なのです
You need allies.
でも 誰が
But who?
四龍の戦士を探しに行かれよう
You must search for the four dragon warriors.
You mean the four dragon warriors of legend?
四龍の戦士って 伝説の
居るの 居るの
They exist?! They really exist?!
Yeah, right. They're from the age of legends.
まさか 神話の時代だぞ
居ますよ
They do exist.
Even now, they live quietly in this kingdom, with the dragon blood they inherited.
彼らは今でもこの国でひっそりと龍の血を受け継いで生きている
彼らが力を貸してくれるでしょう
They will lend you their strength.
神官様 私はハク死なせたくない
Priest, I don't want Hak to die.
けど伝説の龍達はこんな私事で力を貸してくれるかしら
But I'm not sure the legendary dragons
will lend their strength to someone like me.
貴方はあの夜 奇跡的に命を拾い
That night,
you miraculously escaped death.
城から奇跡的に逃げ延び
You miraculously escaped the castle.
この奈落の崖を落ちて 奇跡的に無事でした
And you miraculously survived a fall into this abyss.
それはもう奇跡ではなく
I believe those were not miracles,
but God's will leading you here.
ここへ導かれつ天命だったのだと僕は思います
伝説の四龍をもし見つける事が出来たなら
If you find the legendary dragons,
それは貴方だけ願いだけではなく 天命なのです
it will be not only your wish, but God's will.
天命
God's will...
However,
しかし 天は道を示すだけ
heaven can only show you the way.
You must walk the path yourself.
歩いてゆくのは 貴方自身です
I don't know anything.
私は何も知らない
城の中も 外も
Not about the castle or the rest of the world.
イル陛下はもう目を開けません
King Il will not wake again.
分からない
I don't know.
I love your hair, Yona.
私は好きですよ ヨナの髪
I want to know...
私は知りたい
知らずに通り過ぎた事を
the feelings of others and the many other things...
that I once passed by heedlessly.
色んな人の思いを
強くなりたい
I want to become stronger.
Princess?
姫さん
ハクダメ 寝てなさい
Shove
Hak, don't! You should lie down!
I'm all better now.
もう治りました
I'm not going to die.
死にませんよ 俺は
ハク 私 四龍の血を持つ人に会ってみたい
Hak, I want to meet the people
with the dragons' blood.
会ってどうする
Why meet them?
そんな奴等居ないかもしれないし
They may not exist. And if they do,
they may not be your allies.
いても味方とは限らない
その時はその時よ
I'll worry about it then.
At this rate, I can't even leave this place.
このままでは ここを出る事さえ出来ないもの
何とかして前に進みたいの
I want to move forward somehow.
私も強くなるから
I will become stronger.
私に剣とか弓とか教えて
Teach me to use a sword and bow.
I'll learn.
覚えるから
I don't want to die in this absurd state.
不条理なまま 死ぬのは嫌
お前を失うのはもっと嫌
Even more, I don't want to lose you!
その為なら
To prevent that,
神の力だろうと 私は手に入れたい
I will acquire even the power of the gods.
I'm telling you that I won't die.
死なねぇつってんのに
ま 姫様の思し召しなら
Well, if that's what you want,
I guess I'll take a chance on
God's will or whatever it is.
その天命とやらに賭けますか
ハク 最近いい子ね よしよし
Hak, you've been a good boy lately. There, there.
あんまり近づかないで貰えます
Please don't get too close.
Why?
どうして
Because it's annoying.
鬱陶しいから
What?!
なに
You have more wrinkles.
皺増えてる
You're kidding!
嘘でしょう
If you're angry all the time,
you'll become a wrinkly old lady.
あんまイライラしてると
皺皺のばあさんになって仕舞いますよ
That's none of your business!
余計なお世話よ
今のでまた増えた
Now you have even more!
Hak, you idiot!
心は決まりました
Have you made up your mind?
Yes.
お二人に お願いがあるのです
I have a favor to ask of you two.
ま こんなもんでしょう
Well, that should do it.
Do you see
wakaru kai
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
The same obscure lyrics and background
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
I've always talked ideals
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
イクス
Like supporting others
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
俺にとって あんたの言葉は絶対なんだ
I hope you don't realize too early
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
次回 暁のヨナ 第八話
How irresponsible I was being with my words
hayasuginai you ni
選んだ扉
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
Since my hands are warmer than others'
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
When I hold your hand
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
Next Time
Ik-su,
to me, your words are absolute.
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 8:
Episode 8:   The Chosen Door
The Chosen Door.